BSc GRASIELE ROMANZINI BEZERRA

MASTER STUDENT

Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

■ bezerragrasiele@gmail.com

bezerragrasi.github.io

in grasiele-romanzini-bezerra

Bezerragrasi

PROFILE ____

Grasiele Romanzini Bezerra is curriently cursing a full time master degree at Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Brazil, and she holds a bachelor degree in Physics (2020) from Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS), Brazil. Besides having an advanced knowledge in data science and excellent computational skills, she also has 5 years experience in analyse scientific and social data using a varied range of programming languages, such as python, R and C. Most of her research is focused on astrophysics, cosmology and modified gravity, moreover she also has experience in using sciencemetry to understand and explain social behaviours.

EDUCATION _

Master in Cosmology: Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (In progress).

BSc in Physics, Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil (2020).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Master Student

Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Project: Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion

Aug 2021 - Present

- Supervisor: Dr. Martin Makler
- Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto

Scientific Initiation

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Project: Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravitational Lensing

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Advisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto
- Analyse data of 103 lensing galaxies from 4 different surveys

Internship

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

• Project: Gender Diversity in Science

Jun 2015 - Jul 2019

- Advisor: Dr. Marcia C. B. Barbosa
- Statistical analyses of gender diversity using data of 5 thousand Brazilian scientist

PUBLICATIONS ____

Bezerra, Grasiele Romanzini, Daniela Lazzaro, Aruquia Peixoto, Maria Margaret Lopes, C Andrade, H. J. N. Lopes, and Márcia C. Barbosa (2019). "Female Researchers in Science in Brazil: the Scissors Effect". In: *La Brecha de Género en Matemática, Computación y Ciencias Naturales*. Edited by Lilia Meza Montes and Silvina Ponce Dawson. Mexican Physic Society, pages 55–67.

Ferrari, Nathália C, Raquel Martell, Daniela H Okido, **Grasiele Romanzini**, Viviane Magnan, Márcia C Barbosa, and Carolina Brito (2018). "Geographic and gender diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences". In: *Anais da Academia Brasileira de Ciências* 90.2, pages 2543–2552.

Bezerra, Grasiele and Marcia C Barbosa (2016). "Mulheres na física no brasil". In: *SBF Sociedade Brasileira de Física – 50 anos – 1966 – 2016 (Book of 50 years of the Brazilian physic society)*. Edited by Alicia Ivanissevich and Cássio Leite Vieira. Brazilian Physic Society, pages 132–135.

EVENTS

Oral Presentation - Testing Gravity with Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion: II Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, Aug 2022.

Flash Talk - Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Velocity Dispersion in E-Rings Systems: Cosmology from Home 2022, Jul 2022.

Oral Presentation - Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravitational Lensing: First Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS. Brazil. Oct 2019.

Poster Presentation - Geographic and Gender Diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences: IX Workshop in Complexity of Water and Other Liquids, Federal University of Pelotas, UFPel, Pelotas, RS, Brazil. Nov 2018.

Poster Presentation - Women in Physics in Brazil: VII Workshop in Complexity of Water, Other Liquids and Science Education, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Ararangua, SC, Brazil. Nov 2016.

Poster Presentation - Women in Physics: VI Workshop on Complexity of Water and other Liquids, Federal University of Santa Catarina, Ararangua, SC, Brazil. Nov 2015.

SCHOOLS __

Summer School: Astroinformatics II, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

Summer School: Statistics for Astronomers XVII, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

Winter school: XIII CBPF's winter school, Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. December Aug 2021.

Winter School: Astrophysical Winter 2019, Center for Astrophysics and Cosmology of the UFES, Castelo, ES, Brazil. Aug 2019.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING _____

Jul 2021 - Professional Certificate in Data Science, Harvard.

Jun 2021 - Course - Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau, Duke University.

Aug 2020 - Course - Data-driven Astronomy, The University of Sydney.

Feb 2020 - Course - Introduction to Astronomy, Federal Institute Farroupilha.

grasiele R. Bezerra